call from the senior management we have
with us today Mr. Sanjie Mantri MD and
CEO of the company Mr. Gopal
Balachandran CFO Mr. Anand Singhi Chief
Retail and Government Mr. Girish Nayak
Chief Technology and Health Underwriting
and Claims Mr. Mr. Sep Goradia, Chief
Corporate Solutions International and
Bank assurance and Mr. Goro Vorura,
Chief Reinsurance, Underwriting and
Claims for property and casualty.
Please note that any statements,
comments are made in today's call that
may look like forward-looking statements
are based on the information presently
available to the management and do not
constitute an indication of any future
performance as future involved risks and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed. As a reminder,
all participant lines will be in the
listenon mode and there will be an
opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes. Should
you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star and then zero
on your touchstone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Sanjie Mantri, MD and CEO, ICA Lombard
General Insurance Limited. Thank you and
over to you, sir.
Good evening to each one of you. Thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call for ICAL Lumbard for quarter 3 and
9 months financial year 2026.
At the outset, let me wish you all a
very happy new year and best of health
and happiness.
I would like to give you a brief
overview of the recent economic industry
trends which have shaped the operating
environment over the past few months.
Following that, our CFO Mr. Gopal Balach
Chandan will take you through the
company's financial performance for the
recently concluded quarter and 9 months.
The Indian economy recorded a GDP growth
of 8.2% in quarter 2 up from 7.8 in the
preceding quarter. The expansion was
underpinned by sustained government
capital expenditure coupled with an
increase in private capex rup service
activi services activity and a rebound
in private consumption. Consumption was
further supported by easing inflation
and the GST rationalization implemented
in late September 2025.
Coming to Q3 financial year 2026, the
index of industrial production, IIP data
indicates positivity supported by
manufacturing growth, continued
infrastructure development and a
turnaround in consumer good segment.
eBay bill generation and toll
collections during the same period
recorded growth of 13% and 17% YI
reflecting strong underlying economic
activity. We believe that these high
frequency indicators should auger well
for a commercial line of segmented
by GST rationalization the automo sector
has seen a significant uptick in sales.
According to retail sales data based on
vhan registration, the auto industry
recorded a growth of 19.5% for quarter 3
2026 resulting in a total of 9.4 million
vehicles sold.
Within this private car had seen a
growth of 19.3% translating to 1.3
million vehicles. The two-heer segment
grew by 19.2%
with the 7 million vehicles whereas
commercial vehicles grew by 22.2%.
with 1.1 million vehicle being sold.
Interestingly, the overall growth in the
vehicle sales is the highest in last 12
quarters.
It this growth is more broad-based as
tier three cities and beyond have
demonstrated faster growth in both
private car and two-heer segments. This
is also coraborated by strong growth of
28.8% in tractor sales for the quarter.
Overall, the acceleration in new vehicle
sales for the quarter has also led to a
7.7% growth for calendar year 2025 with
a 28.1 million units being sold.
The landmark decision of exemption of
GST on retail health insurance has
significantly improved affordability and
increased awareness.
The industry has passed on the complete
benefit of GST exemptions to the end
consumers.
This has led to an increase in policy
uptake as more customers are seeing
seeking healthcare protection. Here too,
the growth in retail health appears to
be broad-based across markets and it's
supported by a surge in firsttime buyers
especially for tier 2 and tier three
cities which is a positive for this
sector.
On the regulatory front, the government
of India took a significant step during
the quarter by introducing
forward-looking reforms in the insurance
laws with the passage of Saka Bimma Saki
amendment of insurance laws bill 2025.
While most of these amendments will have
farreaching effects on the insurance
sector over time, a few important
changes pertaining to the insurance act
are as follows. Foreign investment in an
Indian insurance company has enhanced
from 74% to 100% thereby supporting
capital inflows enabling provisions in
the amendment act to facilitate business
other than traditional insurance
underwriting and distribution thereby
allowing insurers to offer holistic risk
management services.
Simplification of provisions relating to
investments of assets.
We are excited about these changes and
we do believe that this should be
structurally positive and would
accelerate the growth and development of
the insurance sector. This will also
facilitate ease of doing business and
provide better protection and risk
management solutions to the policy
holders.
In another significant reform in
November 2025, the government of India
formally made effective four new central
labor codes including the code on social
security 2020. Consequent to this,
benefits like gratuty, leave and cash
etc paid on basic salary are now
required to be paid. This is the new
broader definition of wage.
We believe this changes should translate
into a more resilient workforce and
strengthen employee security over time.
This change has a one-time impact on the
financials which will be covered by
Gopal in his section.
Let me now dwell upon the industry
performance for the period ended 31st
December 2025.
The general insurance industry reported
a GDPI growth of 8.7% for 9 months 2026.
Excluding crop and mass cell segment,
the GDPI growth at 13.3 growth stood at
13.3% for the period 9 month 2026.
Speaking on specific segments within the
industry, commercial segment recorded a
healthy growth of 14.8 8% for 9 month
2026 and 16.3% for quarter 3 2026.
This growth led by strong momentum in
the fire line which grew at 20.1% for 9
month 2026.
As mentioned above, this is driven by an
increase in capex particularly in areas
such as roads, railways and renewable
energy.
The motor segment grew at 8.9% in 9
month 2026
compared to 7.6% in H1 2026. For quarter
3 financial year 2026, the growth stood
at 10.9% supported by festive season
demand and the positive impact of GST
rationalization. Health segment grew at
14.2%
for 9 months 2026 with a strong momentum
of 27.6% 6% growth in quarter 3 of 2026
led by retail health which grew at 33.6%
and group health growth of 23.1%
underscoring strong demand across the
segment.
On the other hand, industry combined
ratio worsened from 113.3%
in H1 of 2025 to 119.2% 2% in H1 of 2026
indicating continued underwriting
pressure. During the same period, IC
core moved from 103.2%
in financial year 2025 to 104.0%
in H1 of 2026, reinforcing a superior
financial performance through
disciplined underwriting.
The motor line of business remains a key
area of stress with the industry core
increasing from 124.8% 8% in H1 of 2025
to 128.5%
in H1 of 2026.
IC alumba demonstrated better portfolio
management in motor insurance with the
combined ratio improving from 108 to
106.9%
during the same period.
I will now proceed to present our
company's performance across key
business segments.
For 9 month 2026, gross domestic premium
income of the company grew by 3.6%
compared to industry growth of 8.7% for
the same period.
Within this for quarter 3 2026 the
company reported a premium growth of
13.3%
compared to industry growth of 11.5%
thereby improving its market share from
8.1% for quarter 3 2025 to 8.3% for
quarter 3 2026
for December 2025 in particular the
company's growth in GDPI was 16.1% in
comparison to the industry growth of
14.4% 4%.
Excluding cross crop and mass health,
the company recorded a growth of 7.5%
during 9 month financial year 2026.
Again the industry growth of 13.3%.
Within this for quarter 3 2025 the
company record a growth of 16.4%
as against the industry growth of 20.1%.
In the commercial line segment, our
growth stood at 7.4%
and 6.8% for quarter 3 2026 and 9 month
respectively. While the industry grew by
16.3% for quarter 3 2026 and 14.8% for 9
month 2026.
We continue to be focused on delivering
profitable growth through disciplined
underwriting, pool and risk selection
and portfolio diversification resulting
in the growth of fire segment by 18.8%
in quarter 3 2026 driven by 27.4% growth
in theme segment.
Further, the company delivered a 19.3%
growth in fire compared to 15.8 industry
growth for the month of December 2025.
In the engineering segment, our growth
stood at 15.2% and 13.3% for quarter 3
2026 and 9 month 2026 respectively.
While the industry during the same
period grew by 11.5%
and 12.9% respectively. This led to we
attaining leadership position in
engineering segment for the 9 month
2026.
On the other side, for 9 months 2026,
the company's growth for marine cargo
and liability segment was not in line
with the industry growth announced on
account of portfolio rationalization.
However, it continued to maintain a
leadership position in these lines.
In motor segment for 9 month, the
company record a growth of 5% whereas
the industry view by 8.9%.
While I while our growth in H1 of 2026
was only 2.2, 2% a rebound was observed
in Q3 2026 driven by an underlying
buoyancy in new motor vehicle sales.
Consequently, the motor segment grew by
9.3% in Q3 2026 supported by a strong
growth of 16.1% in December 2025.
Despite heightened competitive intensity
in the recent quarters, we remain
focused on profitable growth driven by
continuous expansion across distribution
channels and a more granular portfolio
segmentation.
Importantly, the company continues to
maintain it leadership position in the
motor segment with a market share of
10.7% for 9 months 2026.
The company's portfolio motor portfolio
mix of private car, two-wheer and
commercial vehicle stood at 53.6,
25.8% and 20.6% respectively for 9 month
financial year 2026.
In the health segment, the company grew
by 42% and a 13.8% for quarter 3 2026
and for 9 month 2026 respectively as
again the industry growth of 27.6 6% and
14.2% for quarter 3 financial year 2026
and 9 month 2026 respectively.
Our health
business delivered a robust growth of
85.8%
in quarter 3 2026 and 44.8%
in 9 month 2026 significantly
outperforming the industry growth of
33.6% 6% in quarter 3 and 16.5% for 9
month 2026.
Our growth was fueled by new to industry
customer growth of 1.7x for quarter 3
2026 and 1.4 times for 9 month 2026.
Thus, our market share increases to 4%
in 9 month 2026 compared to 3.2% for the
same period in the previous year. And
for quarter 3 2026, our market share has
increased to 4.5%
from 3.2% for the same period in
previous year. The strong performance
has also been driven by sustained
investment in strengthening our retail
distribution capabilities across
channels.
The group health segment registered a
growth of 26.6%
and 5.9% for quarter 3 2026 and 9 month
2026 respectively. While the industry
grew by 23.1% for quarter 3 2026 and
12.6% for 9 months 2026.
I would like to apprise you of certain
strategic initiatives that continue to
drive operational excellence and
customer sensit centricity across the
organization.
The one call center initiative continues
to deliver strong momentum in the
company's transition towards a digital
first do it yourself servicing model. In
December over 60% of the total service
engagements were managed digitally as
against 38% only for 2025. This was
possible due to our inter AI
interventions through various bots which
has helped customers in adopting DIY
service modes.
This has led to improved turn on times,
service consistency and increased
productivity. Our differentiated service
desk initiatives which we can which we
had spoken about in a previous call have
resulted in increase of a call center
NPS to 73 in Q3 of 2026 from 60 in Q1 of
financial year 2026.
Building on a one aisle one digital
framework we continue to take positive
strides toward offering a seamless and
omni channel experience across our
website and the i take care platform as
you might recall the takeare app was
initially launched to provide a
continuum of care for our health
insurance customers over time the app
has continuously evolved with new
functionaries and features making it a
comprehensive one-stop solution for
service and sales across multiple retail
product clients.
The app has now crossed 19.7 million
downloads as of December 31st, 2025,
reflecting growing customer engagement
and dig digital adoption.
The customer registered the the company
registered a UWP of 3.54 billion for 9
month from the I take care app as
against 1.45 billion for the same period
last year. I'll take care has also made
significant progress in addressing key
customer service requirements and
delivering a seamless insurance
experience. Just to highlight for Trip
Secure Plus, our premier travel
insurance product, customers can now
independently manage claims, policy
cancellations, extensions, and
modifications through the app. These
enhancements have enabled 93%
of services service requests to be
processed on DIY basis without the need
for manual intervention
leading to a corresponding reduction in
support call volumes. Notably 79% of
premium intimation for trip secure plus
in December 2025 were also initiated
through take care app as compared to 22%
in July 2025.
In order to continually enhance our
efficiency levels in motor claims, we
have expanded our cashless garage
network from 13,600 plus garages in
quarter 3 2025 to 15,000 garages in
quarter 3 2026.
75.2%
of our nonm claims for quarter 3 2026
were serviced at TPN up from 73.6 in
quarter 3 2025 leading to a enhanced
customer experience.
In the retail segment, 99.6% of our
total claims were paid within 30 days.
And for motor insurance own damage
segment, 96.8% of our claims were paid
within 30 days for the period ended 9
month 2026. As a result, our NPS for H1
2026, for health claims stood at 70, and
for motor claims stood at 69,
reinforcing our position as a
customercentric organization.
In conclusion, the domestic macro
environment remains supportive with
broad-based consumption showing healthy
momentum. We remain focused on building
a sustainable long-term franchise
anchored in the strength of our
technology processes and service
architecture. Through our one team
initiative, we continue to sharpen
execution, drive consistency, and
deliver customer outcomes at scale. We
are well positioned to convert a more
supportive demand environment into a
steady highquality growth while
maintaining discipline in underwriting
service delivery and operating
efficiency. I will now request Gopal to
take you through the financial numbers
for the period 9 month 2026. Uh thanks
Njie and uh good evening to each one of
you. I will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the recently concluded quarter and 9
months. We have uploaded the results
presentation on our website. You all can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers. Uh with effects
from October 1, 2024, long-term products
are accounted on a 1 byN basis as
mandated by a regulator. Please refer to
the investor presentation on slide 16
for a much more detailed information on
comparison of financials on N and 1 by N
basis. Uh now let me update on GDPI
numbers. Please note these numbers are
on 1 byN basis. The GDP of the company
was at uh 213.72 billion rupees in 9
months current year as against rupees
206.23 billion in 9 month FI25 a growth
of 3.6% as against the industry growth
of 8.7%.
GDP of the company was at 70 billion
70.41 41 billion in Q3 FI26 as against
rupees 62.14 billion in Q3 FI25. A
growth of 13.3% as against the industry
growth of 11.5%.
Resulting in our market share to grow
from 8.1% in quarter 3 last year to 8.3%
in quarter 3 of the current year. On the
retail side of the business, GDP of the
motor segment was at rupes 33.99 billion
in Q3 FI26 as against rupes 31.09 09
billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 9.3%.
The advanced premium for motor segment
was at 41.26 billion rupees as at
December 31, 2025 as against rupees
39.13 billion as at September 30, 2025.
GDP of the health segment was at rupes
20.44 in Q3 this year as against rupes
14.53 billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 40.6%.
Within this our retail health segment
registered a robust growth of 85.8%.
During the same period GDP of our
commercial line was at rupes 15.72
billion in Q3 FI26 as against rupees
14.63 billion in Q3 FI25
registering a growth of 7.4%. Our agent
which includes a point of sale
distribution count was 1 lak 50,458
as at December 31 2025 up from 147408
as at September 30 2025. Our combined
ratio on 1 by n basis was 104.2%
in 9 months current year as against
102.9%
in 9 months last year. On an N basis,
our combined ratio was 103.1% in the
current year as against 102.8%
in 9 months last year.
Combined ratio on again 1 by N for this
quarter 3 current year was 104.5%.
as against 102.7%
in Q3 last year again on an end basis
for this year quarter 3 combined ratio
was 103.1
as against 102.3 in Q3 FI25
we have been talking about the impact of
CAT losses if one was to exclude the
impact of CAT losses of rupees 84
billion in 9 months current year and 94
billion in 9 months of last year the
combined ratio on a 1 byN basis was 103
3.7% and 102.3% respectively. The same
numbers on an N basis was 102.6% and
102.2% respectively.
Uh now coming to the quarter excluding
the impact of CAT losses of rupees.11
billion in Q3 current year the combined
ratio on 1 byN was 104.3
and the same numbers on an N basis was
103%.
There were no CAT losses in Q3 FI25s and
as mentioned by Sanjie in his opening
remarks excluding the impact of wage
codes of rupees.55
billion our combined ratio on a 1 byN
basis for 9 months current year and
quarter 3 current year was 103.9%
and 103.5%
respectively.
On a n basis our combined ratio
excluding the wage course wage code
impact was 102.8. 8% and 102.2% for 9
months and Q3 respectively. Our
investment assets during the quarter
rose to rupees 582.96 billion as at
December 31, 2025 up from rupees 562
billion as at September 30, 2025. Our
investment leverage net of borrowing was
3.6 times at December 31, 2025 as
against 3.57 at September 30, 2025.
Investment income was at rupes 37.57
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupes 33.73 billion in 9 months
last year. On a quarterly basis,
investment income was at rupees 12.19
billion in Q3 current year as against
rupes 11.21 billion in Q3 last year. Our
capital gains net of environmental
investment assets stood at rupes 9.33
billion in 9 months current year as
against rupes 7.96 billion in 9 months
last year. Capital gains stood at rupees
3.17 billion in quarter 3 current year
as compared to rups 2.76 billion in Q3
last year. On a 1 byN basis, our PBT
grew by 10.8% at rupees 29.41 billion in
9 months current year as against rupees
26.53 billion in 9 months last year on
an again for the quarter on a 1 by basis
PBT grew by 9.4%
for the current quarter as against rups
9.6 6 billion in Q3 last year.
Consequently, on a 1 byN basis, PAT grew
by 11.3%
at rupees 22.225 billion in 9 months
current year as against rupes 19.99
billion in 9 last year. The same numbers
on an end basis for profit after tax
grew by 13.8% at rupes 22.22 billion in
9 months current year as against rupes
19.53 billion in 9 months last year. On
a oneby basis, fat degrouped by 9.1% at
6.59 billion in Q3 current year from
7.24 billion in Q3 last year. Again
coming back to N basis fact remained
flattish at 6.8 billion in Q3 current
year from 6.79 billion in Q3 last last
year. Excluding the impact of wage code
uh on a 1 byN basis patch was rupes
22.67 67 billion in 9 months current
year and rupes 7 billion in Q3 current
year registering a growth of 13.4% and a
degrowth of 3.3% respectively. The same
numbers on an end basis that was rupees
22.64 billion for 9 months current year
and rupees 7.21 billion in Q3 of this
quarter registering a growth of 15.9%
and 6.3% respectively.
Coming to ROE on a 1 byN basis it was
19.5% in 9 months as against 20.8% in 9
months last year. ROE for the quarter 3
current year was 16.5% as against 21.5%
in Q3 FI25 excluding the wage code
impact on a 1 byN basis ROE was 19.8%
and 17.5% in 9 months and Q3 of the
current year respectively. Tolerance
ratio was at 2.69 69 times at December
31, 2025 as against 2.73 times at
September 30, 2025 continued to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times. As I conclude,
I would like to state that uh we are all
aligned with our ethos of driving
profitable growth, consistent and
sustainable value creation for all of
our stakeholders while ensuring that the
interests of the policy holders are in
the forefront at all times. I'd like to
thank you all for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take any questions that you may have.
Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. We will now begin
with the question and answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and then one on their
touchstone phone.
If you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two. Participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question Q assembles.
Our first question comes from the line
of Suprain Duta from Jeff. Please go
ahead.
>> Hi. Um, thanks for the opportunity. My
first question is on the labor codes.
Um, you know, we understand that you
know there is a 50 cr impact from you
know the labor code changes. Just wanted
to understand what proportion of this is
recurring versus what proportion of this
was one time. You know that was the
first question. Secondly, you know,
coming to growth now, you know, despite
the GST tailwinds, um, you know, the
growth even on the motor side, if I see
has been, you know, slower than what the
industry has, uh, witnessed and I do
understand that, you know, competition
has been elevated. But you know the
regulator at the regulatory level has
taken multiple steps you know be it
extens of management guidelines or you
know discussions with industry you know
to reduce the competitive intensity or
bring in some bit of rationality yet we
are you know not able to see that happen
so from here you know if I'm taking a
two to three year view what will you
know drive growth in the motor segment
for a player like you which already has
10 11% market share you know that's you
know if you could throw some light on
that you know that would be very
helpful. And lastly on the water TP loss
ratio uh I do understand last time there
was a TP release. Uh but uh you know
this time it seems to be a more
normalized loss ratio. Um could we
assume that you know the reserve release
is hold and you know there is no further
release that would come in the fourth
quarter or you know could there be
further releases that would come in the
fourth quarter. You know if you could
throw some light on the reserve release
that would also be helpful. Thank you.
Thanks. Thanks. Thanks for those
questions. Uh on the first one, uh so
far as the labor code is concerned,
obviously uh uh uh the impact of 55
crores uh in that sense is one time
because it's primarily the liability
resulting from an actual valuation for
the past service uh cost uh in so far as
wages is concerned. Having said that,
obviously this code is also evolving. Uh
so hence to that extent we will have to
see if there are any more incremental
guidelines or rules that are that come
into existence. But at this point of
time this is whatever has been released
thus far. This impact of 55 crores is uh
what is the past service uh cost uh
which is more which is a complete impact
that we have taken in the financials of
quarter 3 and 9 months. And if you have
seen also the disclosure that we have
made uh there is an element of roughly
about 17 crores. This is the amount of
unamotized cost uh which will kind of
get uh amotized over the next 3 years
and in line with again the acturial
report. Uh those are the two numbers in
so far as uh the impact of wage code is
concerned. 65 crores is more a one-time
impact in the financials. 17 crores of
amotized cost is something that will get
amotized over the next uh 3 years. So
that's in response to the first one. On
the response to the third question,
motor third party loss ratios. Um I
think I will keep uh keep reiterating
this. Uh what we have told the market is
um overall motor loss ratio range that
we have spoken is between 65 to 67%.
And if you look at uh the 9month numbers
and that is something that we keep
urging that you should keep looking at
year-to- date numbers than more
quarterly outcomes. The 9 month numbers
for the current year motor overall
stands at about 66.3%. This is both own
damage and third party put together. So
it's kind of pretty much playing out in
line with the range that one has spoken
about and hence to that extent uh uh we
are quite happy with the way how things
have progressed to your point on any uh
impact of reserving etc etc. uh again we
will keep uh stressing on the fact that
there has been no change in any of our
actual assumptions and therefore to that
extent it is not that we have done
anything specific whether it was in the
context of last year or even for the
matter of fact when you look at the
numbers from the current year
perspective um so that's in response to
the uh third one and on the second one
uh I will maybe Sanjie yeah I will just
uh so on the motor part uh clearly first
up we are extremely excited with the
positive envir irement that has got
created as I was giving the briefing the
quarter three numbers the growth in
number of vehicles across private car
two-heer as well as CV which was which
has been more than 19% the highest in
last 12 quarters is a very very good
sign uh this increase in number has also
come with the GST rationalization which
made the vehicles cheaper and with that
coming through we had to also realign
what is required and we also spoke about
in terms of how the combine for the
market has moved in motor from 124 which
was hard enough to 128. So the
realignment was a very key piece which
is what we as an organization has done.
Uh consequent to this what we are seeing
is the growth of December in particular
where we have exceeded the market
expectations. We remain very positively
driven overall as to what motor holds
for us. We've closed the year with a
10.7% market share. uh probably a loss
of uh 04 or thereabouts as to what we
had 9 months but as we close the
positivity with which we expect even Q4
numbers to build up on the new sales
would drive growth for us because that
is the combination which we are probably
best at
overall from an environment standpoints
we do see consumption playing a big role
and in that upward mobility of a
two-heer customer seeking private car
and thereabout also is becoming very
clear also So one more point which well
for us is we've been a distributionled
company and the growth is broad-based
which is where they see that beyond ph
and about where the market growth also
is coming it again is a big positive for
us and it will help us to drive what we
want to drive as an agenda. So we are
overall on motor uh very positively
placed but the realignment in wake of
what the intensity is seen is something
which is warranted and we've always
maintained that we'll never shy away
from taking those calls but the range
mount 10.7% market share where we stand
we are pretty much involved as a number
one player as a topmost player we are
also very aware of the responsibility
that we carry in the motor payment in
particular No.
>> Yeah,
>> that's very helpful. Thank you. Thank
you.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. Your next question comes from
the line of Sankit Koda from Aendos
Park. Please go ahead.
>> Uh yeah, thank you for the opportunity.
Uh uh see the retail health growth 85 or
86%age in the third quarter. Um honestly
it has the unwinding portion of last
year too. So if if I do end to end
comparison uh which which is more like
to like so so so the uh can you just
spell out the growth how how the retail
health has panned out uh if you look on
end to- end basis
we not separately calling that out so
honestly uh to that extent I think what
we would say is that uh what we are very
excited is what I think Sanjiv responded
even on motor I think the underlying
demand on ground is kind of pretty much
playing out consequent some of the
rationalizations that have happened in
the context of uh GSTs uh that we have
kind of talked about even in the last
quarter and u and hence to that extent
uh one would say that the growth is very
very uh uh exciting and hence to that
extent while it does have an impact uh
but um honestly our sense is uh I think
broadly even if I were to kind of uh
give a number even on an end basis I
think that growth would be more or less
around the same range of between 80 to
85%. So hence it doesn't kind of change
much uh which is what we had said what
we basically expected is more the
underlying impact momentum than looking
at numbers whether on an end basis or a
one by end basis.
>> Yeah and also you know we talking about
if you look at the numbers we've gone on
80% plus in all three months October
November and December. uh so very
clearly uh the need for differentiating
that and talking as it is it's not an
easy commentary we talking one by hand I
for you to listen on audio itself is a
challenge I can tell you probably you
can make more sense when you have the
script in hand uh but this growth and
what we have been doing over sustained
quarter also is reflected in the market
share which has increased to 4.5% in Q3
uh which is which clearly speaks about
the underlying moment momentum that the
team has been able to build. Uh and if
your question is do you see this
momentum probably playing out even in
quarter 4 my answer would be every
reason to believe and it's dri and again
driven by a very good demand across
markets. So there is a play and we have
a product and we have a team which is
capable of driving this uh transition.
If you asked the beginning of the year
did we expect a uh 4 and a half% of
market share my answer would have been
probably it would have been a shade
lower than that. So there is tailwind
which is also helping us look uh better
than what we could have been but would
we have been far would have been 4%. So
it's it's pretty much there and we are
well set. So we at the right place at
the right time uh as far as health is
concerned.
>> Uh essentially this this I mean honestly
this growth is little extraordinary even
if I look at from the industry um
standard point of view is it any
particular channel or or you which not
present in a particular channel now
exploring the channel has contributed to
the growth
>> so that that that I can explain you that
I can that's what your question was. So
see the product elevate was launched
last last year July. Okay. So we had
started doing well in that and that
renewal base also comes and gets added
to the book. So mathematically plus
supported by the tailwinds there's an
answer to that part. I mean I'm
definitely not saying that 85% of the
growth that will continue over quarters
and quarters. So mathematically speaking
the retention of a product and the
quality product is there then you get
good customers and the retention also is
very high and so there is that part
which is helping us to drive this kind
of a growth.
>> Understood. But but any any new channel
which contributed like like like maybe
you were not present in one
>> pretty of course our agency channel has
opened up significantly and we able to
attract lot more channels. So agency is
uh driving this growth but at the same
time even on website so we've been
pretty across channels uh but the
contribution percentage per se of what
was there would not have gone through a
significant change if you look at the
distribution pattern. So we are seeing
this growth across uh channels uh uh
>> uh no Sanj the reason I'm asking is that
>> and even and even banker for that matter
>> understood understood the reason I'm
asking this question is that is is our
payout structure to the distributor is
more skewed on n basis rather than one
by n basis and then given the
>> no no no we have absolute clarity that
even if it's long-term uh what we will
do is what comes with one by hand as a
as a as a team for us we continue to
operate strictly on those guidelines.
Okay.
>> Okay. Understood. So, so basically
commission payouts are also on online
basis.
>> Sorry to interrupt.
>> Yeah. Yeah. On that. Yes.
>> Okay. Understood. Understood. Thanks.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Madam, so it would be
differentiated to that extent that one
first year would be something and then
second and third year that obviously is
the case but it is distributed this.
>> Understood. Understood. If if I squeeze
in one more sorry
>> sorry to interrupt sir may we request to
return to the queue for followup
questions as there are several other
participants waiting to
>> yes sir
>> thank you so much our next question
comes from the line of pra jin from
motil oal please go ahead
>> uh yeah hi everyone uh questions
>> um just a couple of questions firstly on
the motor side uh we've seen a
tremendous growth in volumes and what
I've understood is there is
premiumization trends as well. uh in
spite of that uh the uh premium growth
of the industry has uh has a decent gap
between the volume growth of the
industry as well as the uh the premium
growth what we have seen right uh so in
that sense what is causing that
disparity and have you seen any further
pricing aggression uh in Q3 with respect
to uh you know motor OD premiums given
that uh you know it was anticipated that
the growth would be there and uh the
competition intensities increased. That
my first question and second question is
in terms of retail health. Could you uh
give us some uh qualitative or some
numbers as around uh as to what is the
kind of growth that is driving the the
new customers that are coming uh what
are they coming at you know what kind of
some assures they are coming and also
the existing customers are they scaling
up the summer assured and maintaining
the premium levels or what's the kind of
uh trajectory that we are seeing there
>> yeah okay so on the motor side Uh
clearly if you see the growth has been
uh broad-based uh and we've seen small
car the small hatchback cars being sold
far higher uh than any other car. So the
the volume growth may not necessarily
translate into a equivalent uh growth in
premium for the industry and also what
has to be noted is that this growth also
is fueled by the rationalization which
happened from 28 to 18%. which itself
led to an impact on the yield per
vehicle going down. So it's the combined
uh thing and that is where the
realignment also had to be done by us as
a team to ensure that what we pick up
overall uh from the market uh with
respect to our own motor portfolio and
also we spoke about how the H1 uh is uh
you know seen the combined ratio getting
that's to answer the competitive
intensity that you're speaking about the
motor combined in 124 and.5 and
thereabouts had very little room to go
further down. It moves down to 128 and
if that is the kind of you know uh
development that comes in there is no
reason to believe that the competition
intensity has gone down and at the same
time you spoke about specific players
coming and coming out. Frankly speaking
our journey is very secular. you know we
we've got a decent understanding and we
back ourselves in terms of what we are
picking up and what we do want to do in
this motor segment in particular uh we
are uh and we have always maintained
that we are very comfortable working
away what is not making basic sense on
the roe level for motor as a book so we
do understand we willing to play the uh
you know game if there's an roe that
comes through even if it's on an
elevated combine but not in a in a in a
random manner where we just keep
acquiring because there's an opportunity
available. So, so that kind of a
discipline is what drives us and that's
where when the industry has moved from
124 to 128 our combine actually improved
by some a percentage and some few more
basis points in that Hmon period also.
So it's it's to be taken in
collaboration while maintaining market
leadership. So uh uh further pricing
aggression very little room but we
maintained that over last couple of
quarters but we are very unsafe because
our journey of how we can slice and dice
and do what makes sense what makes sense
for us uh we we would back ourselves and
we are very confident that we'll be able
to deliver what is warranted for us as a
company
on uh is that P I hope this answers what
you're seeking on motor and and there
is I know TPI is another part which I
must add
>> uh to say which has made the uh yield
look what it is we have been always
expecting it but it's not come through
as yet
>> okay just one thing on the motor before
you kind of answer the retail health uh
the hatchbacks and the smaller cars uh
would you say that g given a lot of them
could be the first time buyers uh
structurally and given you have a large
history of long history of data on the
same kind of vehicles being sold and
first-time buyers would you say that the
loss ratios or could be higher on this
segment going ahead or
>> this we can we can discuss in detail but
the the long answer in I'll make it
short and say the cars have also started
coming with much better safety features
the road also has changed so there a lot
more the salon systems are getting
digitized the uh overlay in terms of
investigating what's gone wrong because
there are cameras everywhere across the
country the surveillance has increased
so there's a lot more pluses there are a
lot more minuses I'm not saying it uh
and these are all the factors that we
are able to use uh to drive what we want
to drive as a team and that's the USP
that we carry right so we won't be too
phased by it uh and if we do seement
going out of And I think our ability to
take a cause probably ahead of the
market is what uh is the what is what
differentiates us uh as a team. I hope
again I'm able to put across what I'm
saying.
>> Absolutely.
>> And on the retail
>> yeah on the retail health clearly we
have seen far more you know awareness. I
think this GST card besides of course
making it more affordable has been the
biggest marketing
you know to make the individuals and
their families to realize that health
insurance is critical and as a trend to
be very honest we do see some insured
increasing significantly we see bulk of
our customers in the range of 7 and a
half to 10 lakh sum insured so which is
a big positive also to just share with
all of you whenever a customer picks up
a higher sum insured their ability to
retain and be with us is much higher
because the quality of the customer is
much better. So yes, it's a big plus for
us uh uh as a company.
>> Thank you so much. Wish you all the
best.
>> Thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. The next question comes from
the line of Ain Singh from MK Global.
Please go ahead.
>> Yeah. Hi, good evening. Uh thanks for
the opportunity. Uh so couple of
question. The first one is looking at
the impact of 1 by n in terms of a
combined ratios. Is it kind of a fair
assumption that the your multi-year
product has seen a very very strong
growth? If you can sort of provide some
color I mean within your retail health
what is the multi-year uh premium
shares. So that's one. Second
kind of a you know that now we are kind
of have seen 9 10 months of the year. uh
so for FI27
uh uh if I have missed I don't know uh
you can provide some kind of uh you know
guidance on growth as well as on
combined and related partly in motor
third party should we expect uh you know
by the time you're queue for some
reserve releases given that I mean your
I mean where your reserving are sitting
or kind of a reserve releases in FY 22
to 24 is still pretty minimal so is it
kind of you know fair to assume that
okay the Q4 should see some motor TP
>> yeah so uh I think I'll go it on the
reverse way uh so motor third party I
think obviously uh yeah uh I think as an
industry we all have been kind of
waiting for the price announcement uh so
we'll wait and see by the time we
announce uh results for the next quarter
hopefully we will see where we where we
land um so we will keep all of you
updated on that uh on the Second piece
on uh what is it that we can expect for
the next year. I think this is something
that we had spoken even in uh as in last
quarter as in to say that I think given
the strong growth momentum that we see
kind of getting rebound back to us. Uh
what we have always maintained is at a
uh at a top line or from a growth
standpoint we have tried to see if we
can be 100 to 200 basis points at a
company level better than the industry
growth numbers. uh this is cutting
across all lines and uh and that is
exactly what possibly you would have
seen uh getting exhibited in quarter 3
uh for us uh in terms of where we our
growth where we the industry growth and
even more specifically if you would have
seen even for the month of December I
think we have had an outperformance with
the overall industry numbers so
therefore that's something that we would
endeavor even as we head into given the
strong growth momentum that one is
seeing on ground and hence to that
extent that is what we would kind of
pencil in in terms of trying to continue
to gain incremental market share on
combined more important than the
combined I think what we have largely
spoken is to try and see if we can
continue to sustain delivering roses in
that in that range of 18 to 20% even if
you would have seen the numbers for the
9 months it's been roughly around 19%
thereabout so hence to that extent uh in
that range of 18 to 20% so that's
something that is something is what we
would look forward again when you look
at uh how we would want to play out even
for the next year uh from an ROE
standpoint uh to your first point I I
think it is a high singledigit number in
terms of the proportion of long-term uh
uh premiums which be the total premium
that we underwrite. Um but um I think
the only thing that we would keep urging
is uh I think even as I was reading the
transcript I did realize there are so
many numbers on an end and a one by n
basis across various parameters. Um so
hence to that extent if you ask us
ideally on a consist this will actually
kind of continue for even maybe for the
next three quarters because while uh
while quarter three of this year onwards
now we everything is on a one by end but
still there will always be a factor of
the first question that was being asked
in terms of what is the impact of acured
of last year in this quarter and so on
and so forth. So hence to that extent a
far better reflection is to keep looking
at numbers on an end basis and there if
you would have seen our combined for
quarter 3 has actually been better. I
think if you look at quarter three of
last year our combined was roughly about
102.3%.
and this number on an end basis for
quarter the current year is point there
I just want to interject and make this
point and uh we accept that also when
when came in as a company uh we don't
want to confuse at any point of time
acknowledge value to accounting you know
we very clear so we have uh uh in all
our conversations with our team and key
personnels who are involved uh we only
discuss on end basis because that is the
true value which will get embedded in
the The what comes because of the uh
accounting part is just an outcome for
us and that is the real value uh you
know value that we can add even our
budgets for that matter that we share
are all taken on end basis uh uh because
that's how portfolio can be picked up in
the right manner and even cash flows can
get generated otherwise the tendency to
make it shorter and shorter would erode
value over long term sorry Yeah,
>> thank you. Thank you.
>> Thanks. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Our next question comes from
the line of Midesh from Invest. Please
go ahead.
Uh thanks for the opportunity. Uh so can
you share the share of new uh in the
motor segment? What is the new and what
is uh old vehicles?
I'm trying to understand whether the
market share trends are more uh the
market share trends how they are shaping
up in both these segments are we have we
lost market share in the new side that
is reflecting into lower growth or or
it's in both both segment our market
share trends are broadly similar
>> so so n just for the benefit of all of
you I'll give you two numbers uh one is
in terms of mix for quarter 3 new is
roughly about 35% renewal is about 65
uh and if you see this numbers for 9
months new is about 33 and renewal book
is about 67. So in that sense relatively
for quarter tree uh the mix is about uh
35 and 65 but more important than the
mix if you ask us I think the point that
we have been talking about given the
underlying growth momentum kind play out
with respect to new vehicle sales and
there again in the same order as in I'll
give you Q3 numbers first our new growth
has been 12.4% 4%. Uh and our old growth
has been 7.7%. Translating to an overall
growth in quarter 3 in motors for a set
about 9.3. These same numbers if you
look at it on a 9-month basis the new
growth was has been 2.5%. The renewal
growth has been 6.2 translating an
overall growth of 5%. So this is exactly
the point that we have been talking
about. I think what we are seeing is
clearly an underlying strong growth
momentum coming coming in with respect
to new vehicle sales. Having said that
that does not mean that for us uh
renewals/ retentions are not important.
I think that's equally very very
important. But what we have been able to
leverage is a combination of both the
underlying growth momentum with respect
to new vehicle sales and then of course
the continued focus on improving
retention as well.
>> Yeah absolutely and uh the fact that the
9 month average is uh when we talk about
new is 2.5 and old is 6.2 Q2 while for
the Q3 uh the number goes the other way
where the new is the growth has been led
by new and as in the past Gopal has been
breaching all new has its own set of
expenses that comes but a blood and loss
ratio and that consequent to that it
will have its uh impact but will have a
long-term value creation for us as a
company. uh in the past for the quarters
that we done always was driven by old
growth and if you go back to our scripts
that we have said we have said our
growth is driven by old so that's a big
transition it's a big plus overall for
us and we have been able to obviously
garner more new uh in the market uh
which has helped us to get this kind of
a growth
>> sure secondly if you can share the loss
ratio in health uh segment wise
>> yeah I was just waiting for somebody to
But anyway uh so uh on uh on uh group
health uh I'll first give the quarter
three numbers and then the 9 month
numbers. First I'll give you the Q3 and
9 month numbers of last year. Group
health uh last year was about 97.2
and uh this number for 9 months of last
year was 97.7.
uh the same group health numbers for
quarter 3 this year was 90.7
and 9 month numbers is 93.2
for retail indemnity that's the other
number that generally gets asked for uh
this again quarter 3 last year retail
indemnity loss ratio was 65%.
This number 9 months was 69.1.
For the current year quarter 3, retail
indemnity loss ratios are 63.1.
9 month loss ratio numbers are 67.3. So
again if you look at uh what we have
been telling the market is on corporate
health or group health generally we have
maintained that we are quite comfortable
running at the book with a mid90s that's
being the that's the threshold that we
have spoken about on the corporate
health and that's exactly how it has
played out on a 9month basis and even
retail health I think the range that we
have generally spoken to the market is
to see if you're able to run the book at
a range between 65 to 70%. I think what
we are quite excited with is the way how
the growth in the book has played out
and the fact that we have kind of
largely seen maybe couple of renewal
cycles play through on the new product
that we kind of launched last year. I
think the good news is I think the
experience that you are seeing on ground
I think is kind of pretty much holding
on to the assumptions that we had kind
of pencled in when we kind of launched
this. So those are the two numbers uh
that I would kind of uh give give away
to others.
>> Sure. And lastly on the health side we
are showing very strong growth but from
a longerterm perspective how should we
uh uh how do we plan to manage the issue
of uh uh old lives getting subsidized by
the new lives and that lead to uh loss
ratio deteriorating over a long period
of time. uh currently we are still a
young company on the health side but as
the growth matures let's say five year
down the line how what is the strategy
to manage the overall loss ratio
so two three data points uh one is that
the penetration of retail health in the
country overall is 5%. Okay, most of us
end up looking at group health as a
funible thing for our retail cover that
awareness is building up and there's a
long play available and it's also linked
to the purchasing power if you believe
that the uh GDP growth the purchasing
power the income tax curve the GST all
are living this there's a significant
road available where the uh growth of
new to the insurance or new to
protection uh will keep seeing a
significant
uh uh traction and also as loss rats
picks up which is very real and you're
absolutely spot on but at the same time
the expense and the commission of
acquisition also goes down. So there is
a counter play that comes in and uh the
the aging book in terms of how it
evolves and develops better medical
solutioning all of that what comes into
play we can talk about that when we meet
again but there is a play available and
that's why we see a uh future as we you
know as we go about it
and there is of course and just to add
to it there's a good uh preventive play
that will also will become a critical
factor for each one of us in our life.
So if there was a and as a company we
would uh be very actively involved.
There's so much more available and so
I'll take care which has got good
traction in real terms. Uh we do believe
that uh we will play a significant role.
Right now it's all setting the policy
and admission is how we interact but
that also is progressively changing. uh
there is a good hobby available uh and
it's not that sitting in our room we
don't play out and simulate as to how
this portion will behave uh two years 3
years five years down the line these are
part of actual actial modelings and we
are well aware of it
>> sure sir that's it from my side thank
you
>> thank you thank you thank you
>> thank you next question comes from the
line of sard Mukharji from BNK
securities. Please go ahead.
>> Hi sir, thank you for the opportunity.
Uh a couple of questions from my side.
First on the uh commission uh our
commission number that has increased uh
sequentially quite substantially. I just
wanted to understand that um whether
this is uh primarily due to our retail
products increasing in the mates or uh
whether you were seeing even in
commercial lines uh where you source to
maybe uh you know agents or brokers that
there has been an increase in
commission. So some color on what you
are seeing on the ground and just
because you know it's also fairly
topical that we are hearing about some
regulatory scrutiny on this side. How do
you see the regulatory landscape playing
out? So that is the first one and uh
secondly on the group employer employee
I mean so as you said uh that uh the
loss ratio numbers uh look fairly
encouraging. So just wanted to
understand that this loss ratio outcome
is this uh more a pricing outcome or is
this that the claims environment has
become benign which is why we are seeing
this and our growth is this like uh also
a function of the base effect because
last year I think we were uh not growing
this business. So uh is that playing out
or have you become fairly more
constructive on this business than you
were earlier? Yeah, these will be my two
questions.
>> Okay, too many things into two
questions. So, yeah.
We'll obviously try and address all of
them. Uh so, on the first one, Swarnab,
I think, uh again, this is something
that we always call out. Um uh and this
is what even Sanjiv just at the end
responded to one of the one of the uh
questions. See our our business has to
be fundamentally looked at in the
context of a loss experience and cost of
acquisition. So therefore to that extent
there are always those nuances that play
out in terms of what mix of business
that you write. Uh relatively I I think
the earlier question that was asked in
terms of the mix between new and renewal
in terms of motor and when I kind of
gave out the data points clearly you
would have seen that the proportion of
uh new was much higher particularly when
you looked at the quarter three numbers
this will be what we had seen for the
whole of 9 months. and new inherently
kind of comes with uh a high cost of
acquisition. Uh and hence to that extent
obviously and more importantly if you
would have seen generally quarter three
is uh is is typically a period of
seasons. So and more so on retail. So
hence any quarter three you go back
you'll always find the cost of
acquisition to be relatively higher than
let's say what you would have seen for
other quarters. So there's obviously an
element of seasonality that plays out
when you look at the commission numbers
on an isolated basis. But what we would
keep saying is to keep looking at it
more on ideally the overall combined
ratio which for us actually has dropped
when you look at the H1 numbers relative
to the industry adverse uh that has
happened but and and the second number
that we keep talking about is more on
the overall expenses of management. uh
so even after considering the impact of
the uh wage code that I spoke about of
roughly about 55 crores uh as at 9
months I think we are kind of pretty
much there uh in so far as the limits
that are laid down by the regulatory
guidelines. So hence to that extent
that's the way we would kind of look at
uh I think we're very very conscious of
what we kind of source and very very
conscious of what loss experience and
the cost of acquisition that comes as a
part of it. uh to the second point on
the regulatory uh uh uh uh evolution on
this. I think honestly we we all have to
kind of wait and see how it plays out. I
think the good news is I think from a
regulatory standpoint the regulator has
been kind of instituting the right set
of guidelines for the industry. I think
a couple of years back when they kind of
introduced this overall threshold on
expensive management that was a step in
the that was a step in the very right
direction of making sure that all
companies all cost put together are well
within that threshold of 30%. And if you
look at basis public disclosures uh
roughly there are still maybe almost 21
out of 34 players are maybe possibly met
the norms there are still a lot of list
of companies which are still in exance
on the expense of management. So
honestly I think what we would want to
see from a market standpoint is to make
sure that every player in the market
stays within the limit on expense of
management and then honestly we will
wait for any subsequent changes that
comes from a uh uh regulatory changes
but we'll be equally kind of committed
to whatever the guidelines that the
regulator lays down. Um so that's in
response to the first point on both
commission increase and what could
happen in terms of regulatory change. to
your second point on the GHI u yes it's
a combination of both I think again this
is something that we have articulated
not only in the context of GHI in
general I think what we have stayed
focused on every line you should see how
we can remain profitable and the very
fact that the loss numbers that I gave
out is a testimony to the fact that we
have been very very careful and
selective in terms of what risk do we
want to underwrite uh equally it's
obviously a combination of uh both the
points that you made it's a combination
of let's say better price in terms of
what we are comfortable underwriting and
two we have our own in-house claims
management team I think they do a
brilliant job in terms of making sure
that once the once a group health
account is underwritten how is it that
we can play a very very important role
in managing the overall loss experience
and at the same time giving delight in
so far as customer experience is
concerned which is again reflective of
the NPS scores that we have kind of
called out uh whether it is motor or
whether it is health uh so that's so
that's how the growth growth has been
reflected and again we will continue to
see that play out even as we head into
quarter four or even for the matter of
fact the next financial year.
>> Right sir and so just on the first
question I wanted to also uh uh check on
the commercial line. So is there any
kind of like for where you have
intermediate source the deal has been
okay commissioning inflation anything is
important. Honestly commercial lines in
general I think uh has been uh if you
remember I think what we have to
commercial lines we have generally have
we have our own relationship team which
acts as a direct interface in so far as
working with corporates are concerned
and hence to that extent uh obviously
relatively that cost of sourcing tends
to be very very low but at the same time
what we also write as a part of the
commercial lines is some of risk uh
which is which tends to be relatively
widely distributed and there there will
be an element of cost of uh distribution
but overall the point that I made when
you look at the loss experience plus the
cost of acquisition put together on the
commercialized book that's a very very
profitable book for us and that's the
way how we look at it again rather than
looking at one element of uh the
business that we source
>> right sir got it that's very helpful
thank you so much sir
>> thank you thanks
>> thank you
we will take the last question from the
line of nin chawat from kotak Please go
ahead.
>> Yeah. Uh thanks for uh taking my
question. Uh you know uh you have a very
impressive growth in retail health and
uh you know we can see an improvement in
uh you know retail uh loss ratios as
well. But uh you know as as we
understand uh you know typically the
lock ratios in retail products are
significantly lower in the first uh you
know 2 3 years and then they kind of
move up from there on. So I would have
kind of said that you know this this
this delta is because of the portfolio
mix. Is it something that the new
policies that are originated are ported
or they are they are originated under
under uh you know uh different covenants
or uh you know is is is the uh you know
is as a cohort level profitability
stable or improving or deteriorating if
you would give some color on that.
So Nish again I think I'll I'll kind of
maintain the same response that I gave
in to the earlier question which is I
think the loss ratio range on retail
health as a company that we are
comfortable running at is between 65 to
70% and so that's the number that we
will keep looking for in terms of how we
are able to stay within that uh to a
large part of in terms of sourcing I
think honestly what we want to do is in
line with let's say some of the uh some
of the discussions that even the
government has been doing to kind
increase uh health care or increase
healthcare penetration consequent to
some of the reforms that they have done
is to kind of improve penetration at
large. So hence I think where we are
kind of largely expanding our
distribution reach which is what we put
out also as a part of the opening
transcript to say that even on health we
are do we do we are seeing let's say an
increase in tire two tire three cities
kind of contributing and these are as we
said new to insurance uh so hence to
that extent I think so far as we are
concerned uh we would want to kind of uh
continue to expand by acquiring a lot
many more new to insurance uh customers
and two and more importantly the earlier
point that I said in terms of our
ability to continue to retain our own
customers is something that we are very
much focused on. So it will be a
combination of those two is what will
continue to drive growth in the retail
book.
>> And just to add to what Gopal is saying
see
uh we've also transformed our own
journey right and we are a multi-line
multi-product company uh for us whether
the c customer comes from the root of
motor or from health uh we are seeing it
from a comprehensive one-stop solution.
We were uh under ball in our offering
for a number of years as far as retail
health is concerned and we know that
going in as we move along uh while we
all know that the loss ratios move
upward as we age and that's that's the
truth which I don't see would change but
at the same time you also know if we are
comprehensively dealing with this
customer the motor loss issue also goes
down I mean just to share with you so
it's a very clear mix and we are very
well placed as a multi- product multi-
company. So what we seeing is getting a
good customer on board and then then
working with them on a lifetime
profitability. So the maths is what
plays out with is what you see because
at times you will see only health at
times you will see only motor but what
we look at it is in a far more
comprehensive offering and with a 2.9%
market share which was just probably 18
months back for us to be a four four and
a half uh where we stand as we exist
quarter three it is just helping us to
build a very well-rounded practice. I'm
not saying it was not wellrounded but
health in particular was always in a
space which was driven by GHI and under
this part we see this as a toggling part
and we see it is a very significant play
in our scheme of thing that's why we got
invested and we we stay positive and
business it's always possible that one
or two lines will have a problem when
covid happened health was all over the
place but motor kind of saved the day
for us so that's the way the portfolio
gets balanced and that's Today we end up
talking about what is it that we can
generate as an ROE.
>> Yeah.
>> Got it. That's that's very
comprehensive. Just uh squeezing a last
one. Uh I'm not sure if you mentioned
this but uh uh you know in case of
health uh you know there is uh you know
the the input tax credit loss because of
GST exemption. Uh so how are you dealing
with that? Are you sharing it with the
distributors or are you absorbing it? Is
that one of the drivers for issues?
>> So, so, so clearly yes, we will have to
realign a cost structure and this is
what we have done. The benefit in
totality of GST rationalization has got
passed on to the customers. Uh, and uh,
we had the benefit of as the volume
grows. Uh, for us it you know in every
line of business motor or health
economies of scale will kick in. We have
a large uh health practice as a company
which is in combined from the employer
employee as well as retail health. Uh so
so definitely we'll do what is it
required toize it and serve the customer
appropriately. Yes.
Are you sharing to the distributor or I
mean of course we have the industry has
shared it's not only about us the all of
us on the general insurance and the
retail health have uh and when the
increased volume is not impacting the
income of the distributor per se. So
there is already a counterplay which is
visible uh which can be seen in terms of
the growth. So it's not that it's one
channel which is getting impacted. Uh
comprehensively we are we are all able
to do better business. So yes it's got
passed on. We have also established a
cost structure because uh both part is
required and today's technology and the
so much which is going on which we have
not spoken but we can talk about it when
we sit onetoone is helping us also to
reduce uh cost per transaction. uh I
don't know when you see the script which
I spoke about as to how uh we've been
able to use uh you know bots uh uh to
get our digital part of serving BI
serving significantly up with the uh you
know operator handling it which is
driven by a lot more inconsistency and
uh you know uh time consumption which
can happen. So there is so much that is
happening. So the cost part will go
down. So we will be able to manage it on
this front very easily.
>> Perfect. That's that's that's very very
reassuring. Uh thank you very much and
all the best.
>> Thank you. Thank you and all the best.
Thank you. Okay. Great. Uh thank you so
much for joining in and uh
>> Okay.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank you. Thank you and have a great
2026. Thank you so much. Thank you.
Thank you on behalf of ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited. That
concludes this conference. Thank you all
for joining us and you may now
disconnect alliance.
>> Thank you. Thank